Before we jump in and learn how to implement the techniques of
在开始学习如何落实
experimental design and recommendation engines ourselves,
实验设计和推荐引擎技巧之前
we're going to hear from Dan,
我们先来采访下 Dan
who's worked as a data scientist for Twitter,
他曾是 Twitter、Airbnb 的数据科学家
Airbnb, and now Coinbase.
现在任职于 Coinbase
We'll get some insight on his experiences running experiments.
我们将请 Dan 说说他在运行实验方面的经验
One of the reasons why experimentation is so hard,
试验很难的原因之一是
there's not just a single algorithm that you can follow,
没有一个可以遵循的统一算法
to be like, "Okay, this is like the test.
就好像 “这就是标准试验
It always works no matter what." Not going to happen.
无论什么情况都可行” 这是不可能的
Fortunately for data scientists. We stop jobs.
幸运的是 对于数据科学家来说我们就有用武之地了
So, instead, acknowledging those concerns and letting
企业可以承认这些顾虑
the data scientists configure certain solutions and also revealing the underlying data.
并让数据科学家提供特定的解决方案来分析底层数据
So, I can say, "All right, here is user ID,
例如“这是用户 ID”
number of things bought,
“这是购买的商品数量”
and they were in the treatment group.
“他们属于实验组”
That's like the low level data that you can then build your own solution on as well,
这些是较低级别的数据 如果还需要进一步处理的话
if that's something you need to do for their case.
你可以继续制定你自己的解决方案
Let's say you have some treatment, some control group,
假设有实验组和对照组
maybe that's for some change to your landing page, or something like that,
或许需要更改下着陆页
or change to some page where a user's making a decision,
或者更改下帮助用户做出决策的页面
and what someone in the treatment group gets
实验组的人士获得的结果
looks different than what somebody in a control group gets or something like that.
看起来与对照组的不一样
So, you get all of these results.
得出这些结果后
How do you determine when you end?
如何判断何时停止实验？
How do you determine, "Okay,
例如
now we have enough data let's turn off the experiment.
“现在我们已经掌握了足够的数据 结束实验吧
Everyone should move to this page.
所有人都应该转到这个页面
We know that this is the better of the pages."
我们确定这个页面效果最好”
Yes, definitely when setting up experiments,
在设置实验时
one of the things we encourage is people to set
建议大家提前设置
up all of the metrics that they can ahead of time.
所有的指标
Especially, indicate one or two that are your decision metrics.
尤其是确定一两个决策性指标
So, basically, you've committed yourself to,
作为判断依据
"All right, if these metrics move in the way that I want them to,
“如果这些指标朝着我期望的方向变化
and are maybe are like core business metrics,
属于核心业务指标
either move positively or not negatively,
朝着正面或反面发展
then it's a situation where I can be pretty confident that I want to watch".
那么肯定需要观察这些指标”
That being said, we also need to make sure that those metrics have enough data.
但是 我们还需要确保这些指标有足够的数据
So, at that point, you have a couple options,
这时候可以有几个选择
first of is doing power calculations ahead of time and
首先提前计算实际数据
making sure that you have enough users to make those decisions.
确保有足够的用户作为支撑 能够做出这些决策
So, for example, you might want to say at that time, "All right,
例如 这时候可以提出
I want to make sure that sales doesn't move more than one percent."
“我希望销量不超过 1%
So, how many users do I need?
我需要多少用户？
Roughly how many people hit my landing page?
大约有多少用户访问了我的落地页？”
I can make a pretty simple projection, just say, "All right,
我可以做出很简单的推测
I'm going to need to run this for two weeks,
例如“我需要运行这个实验两周时间
and at that point it can look at the metrics site designated
这时候就可以观察指定的指标了”
At that point, I think this gets into the teams,
我认为这时候就要涉及团队了
but at that point are you talking to someone else and saying,
你会与其他人讨论吗？
"Here's the data that we have regarding this.
例如“这是我们获取的数据
Now, you make a decision.
请做出决策
Here's our recommendations."
这是我们的建议”
Obviously, there are a lot of parts of the business that you're working with.
所以 你需要与企业的很多其他部门合作
So, do you ultimately make those decisions?
你是最终做出这些决策的人吗？
Does someone else make those decisions?
还是其他人？其他团队？
Is that team thing in a lot of companies?
在企业里 这是数据团队工作吗？
That's a great question. I think there's a lot of variation.
问的好我认为实际情况不尽相同
But largely, product teams typically are running these experiments.
但通常 产品团队会运行这些实验
The data scientists responsible for saying,
数据科学家的职责是
"Okay, these are the things that are relevant to measure,
“这些是要衡量的数据
and here's how we're going to measure them both
我们将从数据流程的角度和统计学的角度
from data flow perspective and a statistical perspective."
这么衡量数据”
At the end, often a product manager ends up making the final decision
最后 通常产品经理需要做出最终决策
with input from the data scientist, engineering implications.
他们会考虑数据科学家的意见、工程影响
Also, if they do need to coordinate across teams,
还要与其他团队协调
if say my change is hurting some other teams metric,
例如某项更改是否会影响到其他团队的指标
there can be a conversation with that other team.
需要与其他团队沟通
That really brings in a lot of communication components to your role as a data scientist,
这么说来 作为数据科学家 你需要与很多同事沟通
that maybe a lot of people don't think that they'll be
很多人在日常工作中可能不需要这么多的沟通环节
doing on a regular basis, which is interesting.
这很有意思